Hello, I'm Laura and welcome to everything and
nothing the video that I record inside me
carriage
For more content and more podcasts you can
Visit my pattern whose link is in the
description
Many thanks to all the patrons
that you help me
You see, I am a pure Madrid native.
I was born and grew up and lived all my life
my life in Madrid
the problem that I don't quite like
I don't like Madrid I don't like Madrid
a lot and many people ask me why
You don't like Madrid Why don't you like it?
Madrid if you are from Madrid why don't you
I like Madrid. What's wrong with the city?
and I say
Well, the truth is that I don't know, I put myself
to think about it and I wouldn't know how to tell you what it is
what I don't like about Madrid
or so it was until a few months ago
You see, I came back from Korea a few months ago.
I'm already in Madrid, this is Madrid and
I came back from Korea two months ago I was
there for a whole year and now that I have lived
I was out of Madrid and I've returned I'm able to
See Madrid with different eyes and it is more for me
easy to realize the things that do
I like and the things I don't like
like it then that's why I'm here today
to answer the question of why not
I like Madrid, you will see Madrid as such
As a city, there is nothing wrong with it, that is to say
If you want to come and visit Madrid, come
because maybe you love Madrid
I have the problem, I'm not in Madrid and why?
Well let's say I am a Spirit
free like that I am a good free spirit
We are all free spirits but I
in particular
cities and specifically Madrid Me
It makes me feel trapped It makes me feel
locked up and now that I've been in Seoul
the capital of Korea I have realized
that a factor of Why makes me feel
so closed is that Madrid is rather
small
at least small compared to Seoul
according to giant
gigantic, I mean, I see the map and I say
what a huge piece of city it is for
to give you an idea, Seoul is a
city with 9
9 9
million inhabitants is worth 9 million
of inhabitants, that's easy to say.
It is said very quickly but it is that if it is
We compare with Madrid Madrid only has
three million inhabitants, which means
It is three times as big and has three times as much
of people which is a bit overwhelming is
a little overwhelming to live in a city
with so many people because there are
many many many people
but Madrid seems to be too small and
When I came back from Korea
I said where are the people is that there are no
people I was very surprised because in
Korea
wherever you go there are people camping
in the Primavera River
full full full of people the river but
which is an outrage. That is, often
I'm overwhelmed by that
Oh what is this
It has been the East tree but let's go that it is
a burden
and it's because there are a lot of people but
Of course, since there are so many people, the city is
much bigger much bigger than
Madrid then of course I have returned from
live in a city
as big as seoul and i've gotten into
Madrid, which is a smaller city
and I say clearly that's why I feel so
locked up that's why I feel like there is no
nothing to do the other day I went from the
retreat to the Toledo Gate
that you say more or less that you go around
half the city like this horizontally
horizontally
Well not anymore
and what was he saying
I've lost my way, I've lost the thread like this
I walked half of Madrid and
It was like 4 kilometers
4 km I took him to the map of Seoul and said
it is that it is
much bigger than that
they have nothing to do with each other, nothing to do with each other
so
That is one of the factors that I
I realized when I came back here that
you see one of the reasons why
Madrid always seemed so small to me
and Seoul is so big that the two
cities have grown in a way
completely different Madrid has
grown radially, let's say I think
which is said like this radial, that is to say Madrid
Well, this is Madrid and around here is the
historic center Vale and Madrid has gone
growing around the historic center
it has been getting bigger and bigger
little by little over the years and they go
enlarging the city but in my opinion
Seoul is quite different because it is
everything is distributed, that is, not everything is there
important here and that's it and to see
Madrid you go here you walk 4 km and you have it
seen everything in Seoul has Palaces by
here temples there the area of the
Olympic sports complex
then it also has the river and it has the
bicycle zone, bike lane
has the bike lane it seems that they are me
attacking but not Good yes but not
So the thing is that Seoul has
many things and Madrid too but in
Madrid are all very close together and in Seoul
are separated So that makes the
city that Seoul feels much more
another thing that helps is that seoul
It has a piece of Rio that will blow your mind and
Madrid does not have a river, but it does have one.
Manzanares no no no river okay no no
River The city has no river and it shows
much the difference of a city with
River and a city without a river in my opinion
A city with a river has more charm
But well, apart from not having a river, Madrid
It has many things, it has restaurants
It has museums, it has parks, it has a
a lot of culture has a lot of
cultural activities to do and
Paco has bars to the sack, that is, you can
go to bars and have a beer anywhere
part or bone
If you like that culture of going out for a drink
something Madrid is a good city which is
The problem is that I don't like that or
I prefer other types of plans.
I prefer to go to the mountains or go to the sea and
Madrid has neither more nor mountains because
the sea is obviously too far away and
The mountain does have the community of
Madrid does have mountains but it is two away
hours by bus or so and there is only one
bus a day so if you don't have
car you can't go to the mountain
According to Seoul, it is quite the opposite.
Winter is freezing cold
because it is full of mountains is the
river and it's like a valley then
It is very cold because it is between
mountains but it is very beautiful because it is
between mountains and you can take the subway
go out and say, look, I feel like it today
climb this one and tomorrow I'll climb the other one
You have a lot of options and it's a
wonderful especially if you like the
nature
So, of course, to me that's not having the
nature so accessible in Madrid Well
I also don't like it, I don't like it
So of course I get bored in Madrid.
I'm bored but in Seoul I had a lot of
things to see because it had the temples and
The palaces had restaurants that
visiting and trying new food had
all the neighborhoods and the new culture that
I wanted to know and here it is like everything is very
seen is a culture in which I have
grown up and well I'm bored something else that
has helped me realize
Why do I like Seoul and not Madrid?
It is that in Madrid, although it is a city
small I live far from the center then
Of course if you live far away to get to the
center
It takes about 40 to 50 minutes and it's a pain.
It's a pain to go downtown every day.
every time I think look I have to go to the
center or I have arranged to meet someone in
the center is that my soul falls from
the feet are such a roll and without
However, in Seoul he didn't just live
relatively close but had
many transportation options
public because he lived in a very
busy that eye then when I had
that going to sleep was the worst thing because
being so busy they were all day
passing cars forward and back
back but for the bus or
The subway was very good because it went down and
were passing by
like 10 different buses without exaggeration
Here it goes Look, one is passing by there
Three pass by and give thanks And then the subway
It's a bit far away but it was there
The city is very well connected, to be honest.
for such a big city
has a very good network
transport, that is not as cheap as
Madrid's transport network in
Madrid we have a wonderful price No
I get tired of repeating it. But well there.
public transport was more expensive
you paid for each trip
and I took advantage and to not pay all the
travels I got the bike pass and
I rode my bike everywhere
So it was very good there you could
ride a bike because there was a lane
flat bike here if you want to ride
bike get ready in Madrid because or
it goes up and down, up and down, up and down, up and down and
you end up with your tongue hanging out Imagine that
you want to go to work by bike if not
you have an electric bike you arrive
sweating like a chicken at work with your
shirt, your jacket and your hair all sweaty
no no no here you can tell us in
bicycle because it is not ready
city to go by bike Maybe
for electric Yes but it is not the same
that in Seoul in Seoul it is very well done
so nothing
saying if I find things that I
They like Madrid and I will make another episode.
talking to another person who does
that he likes Madrid so that he can visit you
say everything wonderful about this
city because I'm sure it has
many things but I don't know them or I don't
I notice them So nothing
I hope you have found out because I have
I've been jumping from branch to branch